Inventory of the Lyn Murray papers, 1941-1987
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Lyn Murray papers
1941-1987
Murray, Lyn, 1909-1989
02928
66.75 cubic ft. (74 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
The Lyn Murray papers contain the musical scores, audiotapes, and professional papers of the Emmy award winning composer Lyn Murray.
Arrangement of the Collection
This collection has been intellectually arranged, and divided into three series.
Biography of Lyn Murray
Lyn Murray (1909-1989) was a conductor, arranger, and producer responsible for writing musical scores for radio, television and motion pictures, and Broadway theatrical productions. In 1950, he moved to Hollywood and began composing scores for feature films, including "The Prowler" (1951), "To Catch a Thief" (1955), and "The Miracle" (1959). His scores for television shows include "The Virginian" (1962), "Daniel Boone" (1964), "The Time Tunnel" (1966) and "Dragnet" (1967). He won an Emmy in 1986 for his score to the National Geographic special "Miraculous Machines."
Scope and Content
The Lyn Murray papers contain hand-written musical scores and audiotapes conducted and arranged by Lyn Murray for the stage, radio, television, and motion pictures from 1941-1987. In addition, the papers also include correspondence, contracts, production files, and photographs. Finally, there are various drafts of his personal journals, that he kept from 1947-1983, that were eventually published under the name “Musician: A Hollywood Journal of Wives, Women, Writers, Lawyers, Directors, Producers and Music.”
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Lyn Murray at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
This material was received from Lyn Murray between 1968 and1989 and from Fred Schiller in 1990.
Access Terms
Composition (Music); Television music.; Motion picture music.; Musical sketches.; Radio music.;; Scores.; Audiotapes.; Arrangers (Musicians); Composers.; Film composers.
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Music; Performing Arts
Container List
- Series I. Professional Papers
  - Correspondence, Contracts, and Finances, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, Contracts, and Finances, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 2)
  - Production Files - Finian's Rainbow, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Production Files - Incident at State Beach, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Production Files - The Miracle, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Production Files - Orpheus in Hell, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Production Files - The Song of Frankenstein, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Production Files - Tusitala, undated (Box 3)
  - Production Files - Tusitala, undated (Box 4)
  - Book Files - Musician: A Hollywood Journal of Wives, Women, Writers, Lawyers, Directors, Producers and Music, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 4)
  - Book Files - Musician: A Hollywood Journal of Wives, Women, Writers, Lawyers, Directors, Producers and Music, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 5)
  - Book Files - Musician: A Hollywood Journal of Wives, Women, Writers, Lawyers, Directors, Producers and Music, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6)
  - Lyn Murray Credits, circa 1986 (Box 6)
  - Biographical Files, 1943-1989 (Box 6)
  - Radio Scripts, 1943-1950 (Box 6)
  - Music Cues, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Programs, circa 1970s-1980s (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Files, circa 1940s-1980s (Box 6)
  - Photographs, circa 1960s-1980s (Box 7)
  - Framed Photographs, Promotional Materials, and Memorbilia, 1963-1986 (Box 8)
  - Framed Photographs, Promotional Materials, and Memorbilia, 1963-1986 (Box 9)
  - Daily Appointment Books, 1947-1979 (Box 74)
- Series II. Music Score Sheets
  - 26 by Corwin, 1941 (Box 48)
  - A Woman for Charley, 1969 (Box 34)
  - Alan King, 1965 (Box 44)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Hour, 1962-1965 (Box 11, 32, 49, 50, 51, 58, 60, 61)
  - Alice in Wonderland, 1965 (Box 44)
  - American Overture, undated (Box 22, 56)
  - Ashes of Mrs. Reasoner, undated (Box 34)
  - The Big Night, 1951 (Box 48)
  - Bob Hope, 1975 (Box 25)
  - Bold Ones: The New Doctors, 1969-1971 (Box 13, 59)
  - The Browning Story, undated (Box 57)
  - Camptown, undated (Box 32)
  - Canon a Go-Go, 1966 (Box 59)
  - Channel 28 Auction, undated (Box 11)
  - Chrysler Theatre - Time of Flight, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Chrysler Theatre - 5th Pass, 1963 (Box 50)
  - Chrysler Theatre - Square Peg, 1964 (Box 52)
  - Cimarron, 1948 (Box 57)
  - Collage for Clarinet and Band, 1966 (Box 37, 46)
  - Columbia Presents Corwin, 1944 (Box 57)
  - Come Fly with Me, 1962 (Box 48)
  - Corwin's Primer, undated (Box 10)
  - Cover Story, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Cromer, undated (Box 59)
  - Dan McGrew, undated (Box 45)
  - Daniel Boone, 1966-1970 (Box 10, 11, 27, 41)
  - Day in the Life of America, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Daybreak, 1945 (Box 57)
  - D-Day the Sixth of June, 1956 (Box 24)
  - Deadly Game, 1970 (Box 13)
  - Destination Mindano, 1968 (Box 19)
  - Document A/777, 1950 (Box 48, 57)
  - Donald O'Connor, undated (Box 45)
  - Don't Push, I'll Change When I'm Ready, undated (Box 40)
  - Double Solitaire, 1973 (Box 35)
  - Dr. Kildare, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Dragnet, 1966 (Box 40, 59)
  - Dream Wife, undated (Box 38)
  - Escape to Zahrain, undated (Box 58)
  - Esther, 1941 (Box 18, 55)
  - Every Boy, 1972 (Box 55)
  - Fables, undated (Box 11, 45)
  - Frontier Circus, 1961 (Box 58)
  - GE Theatre - $200 Parlay, 1961 (Box 34)
  - GE Theatre - Camel's Foot, 1960 (Box 57)
  - GE Theatre - Devil You Saw, 1961 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - Free Wheelers, 1962 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - Go Fight City Hall, 1962 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - Great Alberti, 1961 (Box 57)
  - GE Theatre - Judith, 1960 (Box 57)
  - GE Theatre - Little White Lyle, 1961 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - Man About the House, 1962 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - Open House, 1961 (Box 57)
  - GE Theatre - Roman Kid, 1962 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - The Graduation Dress, 1960 (Box 57)
  - GE Theatre - The Little Hours, 1961 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - The Unstoppable Gray Fox, 1962 (Box 50)
  - GE Theatre - Very Special Girl, 1962 (Box 57)
  - GE Theatre - Wishbook, 1961 (Box 57)
  - Gilbert & Sullivan, undated (Box 50)
  - Grand Banks, undated (Box 22)
  - Great Explorations: John Glenn in Africa, 1967 (Box 10, 48)
  - Gunsmoke, 1960-1965 (Box 44, 47)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - A Breath of Air, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - A Letter to Mr. Priest, 1949 (Box 57)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - A Man for Ages, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - A Man's Mother, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Anna and the King of Siam, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - August Heat, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Barefoot Mailman, 1950 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Berkeley Square, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Cinderella, 1951 (Box 48)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Citadel, 1948 (Box 57)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Colonel Effingham's Raid, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Deepwood, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Elizabeth Captive Princess, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Enchanted Cottage, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Farmer in the Dell, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Girls are Like Boats, 1948 (Box 57)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Golden Herd, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Goodbye Mr. Chips, 1951 (Box 48)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Home to Thanksgiving, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Jamie McRuin, 1950 (Box 31)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Johnny Appleseed, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Joy Street, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Knee Pants, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Last Horizon, 1948 (Box 48)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Marmee, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Mistress of the White House, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Mother, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - My Friend Flicka, 1948 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - National Velvet, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Not Wanted, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Old Soldiers Dive, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Patrick Calls Me Mother, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Pioneer Preacher, 1950 (Box 31)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Prairie Years, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Random Harvest, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Rest and Thankful, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Scudda-Hoo! Scudda-Hey!, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Sleepy Hollow, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Smilin' Through, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Story of Kansas City, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Barker, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Failure, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Final Tribute, 1950 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Green Grass of Wyoming, 1950 (Box 57)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Life of Theodore Roosevelt, 1951 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Long Love, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Long Winter, 1951 (Box 49)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Virginian, 1949 (Box 52)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - The Way West, 1950 (Box 57)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Two Years Before the Mast, 1951 (Box 46)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Wayfarer, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - West of the Hill, 1950 (Box 55)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Wild Swans, 1948 (Box 52)
  - Have Gun - Will Tavel, 1960-1961 (Box 47, 58)
  - Hercule Poirot, 1962 (Box 19)
  - Hollywood Television Theatre - Gondola, 1973 (Box 29)
  - Hollywood Television Theatre - Incident at Vichy, undated (Box 35)
  - Hollywood Television Theatre - Steambath, 1973 (Box 29, 56)
  - Hope Album, undated (Box 45)
  - How to Break into Movies, undated (Box 11)
  - Ignatius, undated (Box 24)
  - Incident at State Beach, 1965 (Box 32, 37)
  - It Takes a Thief, 1969 (Box 27, 32)
  - Jacques Cousteau - Hippo, undated (Box 35)
  - Jamison's Kids, 1970 (Box 41)
  - Jesse James, 1966 (Box 27)
  - The John Forsythe Show, 1966 (Box 13, 44)
  - Kate Bliss, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Kraft Mystery Theatre - Talk to my Parnter, 1963 (Box 50)
  - Kraft Suspension Theatre - In Darkness Waiting, 1964 (Box 51)
  - La Bohema, undated (Box 25)
  - Ladies of the Corridor, 1975 (Box 56)
  - Laredo, 1966 (Box 13)
  - Last of Mrs. Lincoln, 1976 (Box 34, 58)
  - Laurel & Hardy, undated (Box 38)
  - Liberation, undated (Box 59)
  - Lincoln, 1974 (Box 17, 34, 42, 56)
  - Long Hot Summer, undated (Box 16)
  - Love Hate Love, 1970 (Box 56)
  - Luxembourg, undated (Box 45)
  - Magic Carpet, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Mannix, 1970 (Box 25)
  - Matt Lincoln, 1970 (Box 13, 25)
  - Medical Center, 1976 (Box 21)
  - Men from Shiloh, 1970 (Box 55)
  - The Miracle, 1964 (Box 31, 34, 47, 51, 56, 59, 60)
  - Mirror to Mirror, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Hymns, undated (Box 37)
  - Miscellaneous Scores, undated (Box 10, 11, 14, 18, 23, 25, 26, 30, 32, 46, 48, 55, 59, 61)
  - Moulin Rouge, 1952 (Box 18)
  - Mysteries of the Great Pyramids, 1977 (Box 21)
  - National Geographic Special - Egypt: Quest for Eternity, 1982 (Box 16)
  - National Geographic Special - Jerusalem, undated (Box 12)
  - National Geographic Special - Miraculous Machines, 1985 (Box 12)
  - National Geographic Special - Return to Everest, undated (Box 12)
  - National Geographic Special - Save the Panda, undated (Box 12)
  - National Geographic Special - Superliners, 1980 (Box 28)
  - National Geographic Special - The Amazon, 1968 (Box 48, 49)
  - National Geographic Special - The Lonely Doryman, 1968 (Box 27, 48, 49)
  - National Geographic Special - Tigris Expedition, 1979 (Box 30)
  - National Geographic Special - Treasures from the Past, undated (Box 17, 21)
  - New Explorers: Costa Rica, 1972 (Box 55)
  - Novak, undated (Box 31)
  - Now You See It, Now You Don't, 1967 (Box 24, 36)
  - October Morning, undated (Box 57)
  - On the Threshold of Space, undated (Box 24)
  - Orpheus in Hell, 1982 (Box 24, 46, 61)
  - Owen Marshall, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Peg O' My Heart, undated (Box 24)
  - Period of Adjustment, 1962 (Box 24)
  - Pleasure Island, 1962 (Box 54)
  - Primal Man, undated (Box 42)
  - Promise Her Anything, 1966 (Box 49)
  - The Prowler, 1951 (Box 24, 58)
  - Rawhide, 1965 (Box 39)
  - Rebecca of Sunnybrook Farm, 1976 (Box 34)
  - Requiem for a Nun, 1975 (Box 56)
  - Ronald Searle Suite, 1962 (Box 59)
  - Rosie, undated (Box 44)
  - Run, Jack, Run, 1965 (Box 39)
  - Sea Gypsies, 1978 (Box 28)
  - Sendrey Greek, undated (Box 44)
  - Separate Lives, undated (Box 38)
  - Shiloh Valentines, 1970 (Box 41)
  - Signpost to Murder, 1964 (Box 48, 58)
  - The Smugglers, 1961 (Box 15)
  - Snow White and the Three Stooges, 1961 (Box 29)
  - Son of Paleface, 1952 (Box 54)
  - Song of Frankenstein, 1981 (Box 53)
  - Songs of Samoa, 1968 (Box 59)
  - Spectre, undated (Box 24)
  - Time of Man, 1969 (Box 34, 59)
  - The Time Tunnel, 1966 (Box 18)
  - To Catch a Thief, 1955 (Box 22, 48)
  - TV Themes, undated (Box 55)
  - The Twilight Zone, 1960 (Box 47)
  - Undersea World of Jacques Cousteau, 1971 (Box 13)
  - Vegas, undated (Box 11)
  - The Virginian, 1964 (Box 43, 52)
  - Wagon Train, 1965 (Box 44)
  - What is the Answer, 1968 (Box 57)
  - Williamsburg, undated (Box 24)
  - Wind in the Willows, undated (Box 44)
  - Wives and Lovers, 1963 (Box 54)
  - The Young Lawyers, 1971 (Box 13)
- Series III. Music Audio Recordings
  - 2 Whitney, 1 Space, undated (Box 73)
  - A Day in the Life of America, undated (Box 63)
  - A Flight to Remember, 1973 (Box 70)
  - A Woman for Charlie, 1969 (Box 70, 73)
  - Africa Expeditions, undated (Box 73)
  - Alfred Hitchcock Hour, 1962-1965 (Box 64, 65, 69, 71)
  - Alice in Wonderland, 1965 (Box 62, 66, 68, 73)
  - An Angel in my Pocket, 1968 (Box 63)
  - Ashes, 1975 (Box 73)
  - Baby You're the One, undated (Box 68)
  - Bain Party, undated (Box 63)
  - The Bible, undated (Box 63, 66)
  - Big Night, undated (Box 66)
  - The Bold Ones, undated (Box 66, 68)
  - Born of Fire, undated (Box 67)
  - Christopher London, 1950 (Box 62)
  - Chrysler Theatre - Time of Flight, undated (Box 64)
  - Cold Spring, undated (Box 69)
  - Come Fly With Me, 1963 (Box 72)
  - Concrete, undated (Box 73)
  - Costa Rica, undated (Box 70)
  - Cover Story, 1980 (Box 67)
  - Cromer, undated (Box 70)
  - Daniel Boone, 1966-1970 (Box 64)
  - Destination Mindanao, 1968 (Box 63, 65)
  - Document A/777, 1950 (Box 72)
  - Double Solitaire, undated (Box 73)
  - Dragnet, 1966 (Box 72)
  - Dream Wife, undated (Box 72)
  - Earnest, undated (Box 70)
  - Esther, 1941 (Box 70)
  - Fables, undated (Box 66, 68)
  - Finian's Rainbow, 1947 (Box 65, 66)
  - Ford Theatre - Crazy Girl, 1948 (Box 62)
  - Freburg USA, undated (Box 68)
  - Gluskin Anthology, undated (Box 70)
  - Gondola, 1973 (Box 70)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Berkeley Square, 1949 (Box 73)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Clay Shattered Door, 1949 (Box 62)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Goodbye Mr. Chips, 1951 (Box 73)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Lost Horizon, 1948 (Box 62)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Morning Glory, 1948 (Box 62)
  - Hallmark Playhouse - Random Harvest, 1949 (Box 73)
  - Hannibal, undated (Box 64)
  - Have Gun - Will Travel, 1960 (Box 64, 70)
  - Haye's Sax, undated (Box 70)
  - Hercule Poirot, 1962 (Box 64)
  - Hope, undated (Box 68)
  - How to Break into the Movies, undated (Box 63)
  - Ice, 1961-1965 (Box 69)
  - Ice Capades, 1962 (Box 64)
  - Ignatius, undated (Box 70)
  - Incident at State Beach, 1965 (Box 72)
  - International Harvester, 1946 (Box 62)
  - It Takes a Thief, 1967 (Box 64, 66, 68)
  - Jacques Cousteau - Hippo, undated (Box 70)
  - The John Forysthe Show, 1966 (Box 64)
  - Johnny Mercer, undated (Box 68)
  - Judith, undated (Box 72)
  - Ladies of the Corridor, 1975 (Box 70)
  - Laurel & Hardy, undated (Box 66)
  - Legacy of Fear, undated (Box 66)
  - LIA, undated (Box 66)
  - Lincoln, 1974 (Box 67, 68)
  - Loulie, undated (Box 68, 70, 73)
  - Love, Hate, Love, 1970 (Box 70)
  - Luxembourg, undated (Box 62)
  - Magic Carpet, 1971 (Box 65, 66)
  - Midnight Oil, 1967 (Box 64, 65)
  - The Miracle, 1964 (Box 72, 73)
  - Miracle Oneonta, 1961 (Box 73)
  - Mirror to Mirror, 1975 (Box 67)
  - Miscellaneous Recordings, undated (Box 63, 65, 67, 73)
  - Movie Primer, undated (Box 73)
  - Mysteries of the Great Pyramids, 1967 (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - The Amazon, undated (Box 73)
  - National Geographic Special - Egypt, 1981 (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - Jerusalem, 1986 (Box 63)
  - National Geographic Special - The Lonely Doryman, 1968 (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - Return to Everest, undated (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - Save the Pandas, undated (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - Superliners, 1980 (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - Tigris Expedition, 1979 (Box 67)
  - National Geographic Special - Treasures of the Past, 1987 (Box 63, 67)
  - Novak, undated (Box 66)
  - One Lovely Step, 1971 (Box 72)
  - Orpheus in Hell, undated (Box 67, 68)
  - Outtakes, undated (Box 64)
  - P.I., undated (Box 66)
  - The Politicain, undated (Box 66)
  - Potpourri, undated (Box 68)
  - Primal Man, undated (Box 67, 70)
  - Prom Album, undated (Box 62)
  - Promise Her Anything, 1966 (Box 71)
  - The Prowler, 1951 (Box 66, 73)
  - Radio Primer, undated (Box 70, 73)
  - Requiem for a Nun, 1975 (Box 70)
  - Rosie, undated (Box 71, 73)
  - Sea Gypsies, 1978 (Box 67)
  - Sealtest, undated (Box 70)
  - Searle St., undated (Box 67)
  - Shakespeare, undated (Box 68)
  - Shower, undated (Box 71)
  - Signpost to Murder, 1964 (Box 66, 71, 72)
  - Sing We Now, 1987 (Box 63, 68, 70)
  - Slaughter, undated (Box 70)
  - The Smugglers, 1966 (Box 63)
  - Song of Frankenstein, 1981 (Box 62, 66, 69)
  - Songs of Samoa, undated (Box 62, 66, 67, 70)
  - Spectre, undated (Box 62, 67)
  - Splendor Grass, undated (Box 68)
  - Start of the Grand Banks, undated (Box 67)
  - Steambath, 1973 (Box 73)
  - Stevenson, 1965 (Box 69)
  - Time of Man, undated (Box 66, 70, 72, 73)
  - To Catch a Thief, undated (Box 71, 72)
  - Tusitala, undated (Box 66, 68, 69)
  - UCLA Incident, 1969 (Box 73)
  - Undersea World of Jacques Cousteau, 1971 (Box 64)
  - Vegas, undated (Box 66)
  - The Virginian, 1964 (Box 68, 72, 73)
  - Voice of God, undated (Box 70)
  - Welk, undated (Box 69)
  - Wind in the Willows, undated (Box 70)
  - Wolper, undated (Box 72)
  - Your All-Time Hit Parade, 1943 (Box 62)